I couldn't say goodbye
Ienai ienai sayonara nante
even though I love you so much
Konna ni daisuki na no ni
You said we should break up
Mou wakareyou to
Kimi no koe ga kikoeta shunkan
and when I heard that
my world turned white in an instant
Mou masshiro ni natte
Karadajuu ni hashitta hibana
and sparks danced in my vision
Is forgetting you what I need
Kimi no koto wo wasureru koto ga
Mae ni susundeku koto na no?
to move on?
I could cry now, I don't understand
Wakaranai yo nakete kuru yo
Let's live in the moment, only in the moment
Seiippai meiippai ima wo ikiyou
We lived like that until now, too, I guess
Sou yatte ikite kita kedo
I couldn't say goodbye
Ienai ienai sayonara nante
Konna ni daisuki na no ni
even though I love you so much
（左門）不破真広→
Fuwa Mahiro,
could you kill Takigawa Yoshino?
お前は　滝川吉野を殺せるか？
（不破真広）ふっ。　なんだよ　それ。
What the hell?
That's not even a funny joke.
ジョークにしても笑えねぇ。
好んで戯れ言を言う趣味はない。
くっ…。
I rarely jest.
（左門）
まあ　おいおいと説明しよう。→
Well, let me explain.
着替えるといい。
Go ahead and change.
あっ。
（左門）安心しろ。
Do not worry.
傷は完治させた。
I have healed your wounds.
I also healed any old injuries or broken bones.
ついでに
古傷や骨折痕も治してやったぞ。
で　今日は　何月何日だ？
So? What's the date?
１月１日だ。→
January 1st.
Episode 14
Happy New Year
あけましておめでとう。
Happy New Year.
（滝川吉野）
正月早々　お墓参りに行くのって→
We may be the only people who would visit a grave first thing on January 1st.
僕たちくらいかも。
（葉風）２年後か…。
ん？
It's been two years...
（葉風）
私が迎える由のなかった正月だ。→
I shouldn't even be around to celebrate this New Year.
Considering that I was meant to be dead on that island two years ago.
本来　２年前に　私は→
無人島で
朽ちていたはずだったのだからな。
あっ　そういうことになるのか。
I guess that's true.
（葉風）お前のおかげだ。
えっ？
It's all thanks to you.
Huh?
I mean... you and Mahiro.
いや…　「真広とお前の」だな。
（左門）はじまりの樹が
どう世界を変えたか→
The princess is traveling to various places
to see for herself
それを　自分の目で確かめるため→
how the Tree of Genesis has changed the world.
今　姫様は　あちこち回っている。
なんで　それに吉野が？
So why did Yoshino go with her?
姫様が同行を許したのが→
The only one the princess would allow to accompany her
滝川吉野だけだったのだ。
was Takigawa Yoshino.
ふっ　随分と
気に入られたもんじゃねぇか。
Sounds like she's taken quite a liking to him.
それが　笑い事では済まぬ火種と
なりつつある。
However,
that is gradually becoming a serious situation.
（山本）待ってたのよ～。→
Hey, we've been waiting!
Come on, have a seat.
さっ　座って　座って。
楽しげなメンツだな。
What a merry gathering this is.
（左門）
私が命じぬかぎりは　静かな男だ。
He's a man of restraint unless I order otherwise.
He'd better be.
当たり前だ。　こんなとこで
槍を振り回されてたまるかよ。
If he starts waving his damn spear around, it won't end well.
（左門）胃腸も弱っておらんはずだ。
気にせず食べろ。
You should be fairly hungry. Help yourself.
そいつも　魔法のおかげか？
Is all this from magic, too?
あっ　初対面だった？
Oh, you two haven't met yet.
He hasn't met me,
（早河）一方的にだが
私は　君を目にしている。
but I've seen him.
If only on the monitor when he was heading to Mt. Fuji.
富士に向かう途中で
軍のモニター越しだったがね。
Hayakawa Takumi,
早河巧。　黒鉄病対策本部長補佐→
Assistant Director of the Black Iron Syndrome Countermeasures Force.
あの時点ではね。
過去形かよ。
Well, he was.
Past tense?
（早河）あれだけの軍を動員し
結果がどうなったか→
This disaster happened under my command after I mobilized a massive force.
君が
意識を失う以前の状況だけでも→
Even though you lost consciousness for part of it, I'm sure you can guess what happened.
おおむね　見当がつくはずだ。
Now he's a bureaucrat in charge of assembling statistical reports on the Black Iron Syndrome.
今じゃ　黒鉄病関連の
統計資料作成係って閑職。
So at the moment, all he can do
絶園の魔法使いのうわさを→
is spread online rumors about the mage of Exodus.
ネットに流すくらいしか
できないってわけ。
The mage of Exodus?
絶園の魔法使い…。
Does one really exist?
そんなのが　本当にいるのか？
（左門）それを
あぶり出すためにやっている。→
We're spreading rumors to figure that out.
If one exists,
実在するとすれば
新たな混乱を避けるため→
we want to find him first, before there is further chaos.
いち早く捜し出し
こちらの管理下に置かねばならん。
We'll have to put him under our control.
Unable to Send Text
Send             Again
It's not fair of you to refuse text messages, Yu...
（羽村・心の声）≪メールまで拒否って
そりゃないよ　ゆっちゃん≫
≪あの樹が現れたとき
大きな犠牲が払われたけど→
When the Tree appeared, there were lots of victims.
それから
確かに　世界は平和になった≫
But it's also true that the world became peaceful after that.
There are many who worship the Tree,
≪樹のことを崇める人も
少なくないけど…≫
though every day, there are more and more rumors about a mage of Exodus
≪でも　一方で
その樹を倒し　この世界を救う→
The Tree that appeared before us
is our savior.
I don't know if you're a brainless Tree follower or just a troll, but it's true that war has stopped.
The Tree that appeared before us
is our savior.
I don't know if you're a brainless Tree follower or just a troll, but it's true that war has stopped.
The Tree that appeared before us
is our savior.
I don't know if you're a brainless Tree follower or just a troll, but it's true that war has stopped.
The Tree that appeared before us
is our savior.
I don't know if you're a brainless Tree follower or just a troll, but it's true that war has stopped.
The Tree that appeared before us
is our savior.
I don't know if you're a brainless Tree follower or just a troll, but it's true that war has stopped.
The Tree that appeared before us
is our savior.
I don't know if you're a brainless Tree follower or just a troll, but it's true that war has stopped.
The Tree that appeared before us
is our savior.
I don't know if you're a brainless Tree follower or just a troll, but it's true that war has stopped.
絶園の樹の魔法使いが
いるってうわさも→
who can defeat the Tree and restore the world to its previous state.
日ごとに広まっている≫
≪なんとなく
みんな　感じてるんだ→
I think people are finally realizing
that the Tree is ruling over us.
僕らは
樹に支配されてしまったって≫
Fuwa Family Grave
≪愛花ちゃん→
Aika,
this began as a journey to find your killer.
君を殺した犯人を
捜す旅だったのに→
今じゃ　とんでもなく
大げさなことになってるよ≫
But it's become such a mess.
≪世の中も
随分　変わってしまって…≫
The world has changed quite a bit.
吉野　不破愛花とは
どういう娘だったのだ？
Yoshino...
What kind of person was Fuwa Aika?
えっと…　ほら→
Um...
Well, she is Mahiro's sister.
あの真広の妹ですから…。
たちが悪そうな娘ということか？
As in, she was also a very difficult person?
悪かったですね。
ん？
Yeah, she was.
Yoshino.
吉野。
ん？
愛花嬢の彼氏に
私も一度　会わせてくれ。
Please introduce me to Aika's boyfriend.
Huh?
えっ？
あの真広の妹と→
To secretly date Mahiro's younger sister,
隠れてつきあうとは
なんとも　命知らずなヤツだ。
that idiot must have no sense of self-preservation.
顔が見てみたい。
I'd love to meet him.
So I'm apparently an idiot with no sense of self-preservation.
≪僕が　その
命知らずの彼氏なんですけどね≫
不破愛花
また改めて謝罪に参ろう。
Fuwa Aika, let me apologize once more.
事によると　お前を死なせたのは
私かもしれん。→
It is possible that I caused your death.
いや→
私は　一体　どれだけの命を→
In truth,
I wonder how many lost lives I've been responsible for.
犠牲にしてしまったのだ？
≪富士に現れたのが→
If it really was the Tree of Exodus that appeared at Mt. Fuji...
ほんとに
絶園の樹だっていうんなら→
Maybe if we could revive it fully, we'd be able to save the world.
完全に復活させれば
世界が元に戻るかも≫
≪僕がやれるのかな？≫
I wonder if I could actually do that.
≪でも　それができたら→
If I did,
maybe my girlfriend would come back!
彼女が
戻ってきてくれるかもしれない≫
（葉風）
この街で暮らしていたのだな。
So this is the city where you lived.
ええ　まあ…。
It is.
I'm sure this place holds many memories.
（葉風）
思い出すことは　いろいろあろう？
Probably more bad ones than good ones.
思い出したくないことの方が
多いかも。
≪今の葉風さんは　おそらく→
Right now, I think Ms. Hakaze
fears the power of the Tree of Genesis more than anyone else.
誰よりも
はじまりの樹の力を恐れている≫
≪僕たちが倒れたあと
絶園の樹を抑え→
We were told that after we'd passed out,
Ms. Hakaze suppressed the Tree of Exodus and stopped the Tree of Genesis.
はじまりの樹の活動を止めたのも
葉風さんだという≫
This isn't your fault, Ms. Hakaze.
葉風さんのせいじゃありませんよ。
No one could have predicted that this would happen.
こんなことになるなんて
誰も予想できやしません。
You may not understand because you were asleep at the time,
お前は　眠っていたから
実感として分からぬであろうが→
but it only took seven days.
たった７日だ。
破壊の跡が僅かに残るだけで→
Only traces of the destruction remained,
１週間で
世界の大半が　元に戻ったのだ。→
with most of the world returning to normal in a week.
金属化した死体も　はじまりの樹が
吸収して消え去り→
The metallicized bodies
were all absorbed by the Tree of Genesis and vanished.
And I hear that most social problems have pretty much disappeared.
社会生活にも　ほとんど
問題がなくなったと聞く。→
むしろ　そのことの方が恐ろしい。
Somehow, that frightens me even more.
私は
はじまりの樹の力を見誤っていた。
I underestimated the Tree of Genesis's power.
If this is what happened with only a portion of the Tree awake,
ただ一部が目覚めただけで
これだけのことが起きたのだ。
完全覚醒すれば　どうなるか…。
what would have happened had it fully revived?
But because it was only partially revived,
中途半端に目覚めたせいで→
it's also possible that meant more victims.
変に
犠牲が出たのかもしれませんよ。
Yeah.
But the more I see, the less I'm certain as to what is right.
だが　私は　見れば見るほど
何が正しいか分からなくなる。
Your home and your friends have all disappeared.
お前の故郷も　友人たちも→
こうして奪ってしまった。
ほかにも　きっと…。
And there must be many more.
Let's get away from here.
ここを離れましょう。
お正月なんですから
おいしいものでも食べましょうよ。
Since it's New Year's, let's go get something good to eat.
葉風が吉野にほれた!?
Hakaze has a crush on Yoshino?!
The princess does not seem to realize
（左門）
それが　どういう感情であるか→
おそらく
姫様は気付いてないだろう。
her current feelings.
Despite how she seems, the princess was rather sheltered.
姫様は　あれで　箱入り娘なのだ。→
はじまりの樹に守られた姫宮。→
She was protected by the Tree of Genesis.
だからこそ
あの富士山麓での窮地は→
So what she experienced at Mt. Fuji
may have been her first taste of hardship.
姫様が初めて味わった
逆境だったと言える。
Well, you're the one to blame for all that.
お前が　その状況に
落とし込んだんだけどな。
And the one who saved her was Takigawa Yoshino.
そこを救ったのが滝川吉野だ。
スルーかよ…。
You're ignoring me?
（左門）姫様さえ絶望した状況に
果敢に立ち向かい→
When even she despaired, he persevered and found a way out.
見事　道を切り開いた彼は→
So to the princess, he is the first reliable man in her life.
姫様にとって　初めての
頼れる男だったと言える。→
ほれん方がおかしい。
だとしても→
Why wouldn't she fall for him?
Even so, how does any of this lead to killing him?
どっから　それが
吉野を殺せって話になるんだよ。
（葉風）吉野。
ん？
Yoshino.
I will tell you the other reason I had you accompany me on this trip.
お前にだけ　旅に出た
もう一つの目的を教えておく。
絶園の樹を
完全に復活させるには→
For the Tree of Exodus to fully revive,
it must absorb the remaining fruit.
残りの果実を
吸収させねばならない。→
Thus, we need to track them down.
その所在を確かめるためにも
各地を回る必要があった。
葉風さん…。
あっ。
Ms. Hakaze...
万一のためだ。
It's only a precaution.
（左門）姫様は揺れておられる。
The princess is uncertain.
パン　パン
（左門）己の力を恐れ→
She fears the world,
この先どうするべきか
迷っておられる。
and is unsure as to what she should do next.
Are you trying to say
吉野の意見で
この先どうするか決めるとでも？
that Yoshino's opinion may be a deciding factor?
大きく左右されような。→
I believe he could greatly sway her choice.
If Takigawa Yoshino says
滝川吉野が　はじまりの樹を→
she should revive the Tree of Genesis, she will probably do it.
覚醒させるべきと言えば
そうされるだろうし→
べきでないと言えば
そうされよう。
And if he says she shouldn't, she will probably agree.
ふっ。　ほれた弱みってやつか。
Then she's a sucker for the guy she loves.
Is that not what it means to have your heart stolen?
心を奪われるとは
そういうことだろう？
今や姫様は→
Currently, the princess
滝川吉野を中心に
物事を考えているのだ。
makes every decision with Takigawa Yoshino in mind.
はぁ～。　つまり…。
Meaning...
The fate of the world has somehow ended up in Yoshino's hands.
世界の命運は
吉野が握っちまったってことか。
（葉風）吉野　少し待っててくれ。
はい。
Yoshino, please wait for a moment.
Sure.
≫（羽村）ごめん。
ん？
Excuse me.
ちょっといいかな？
Do you have a moment?
≪なっておらん…≫
This isn't good.
≪また　吉野の前で
情けないところを見せてしまった≫
I keep acting like a fool in front of him.
And he has no obligation to listen to me!
≪そもそも　吉野が
私に従う義理も　すでにない≫
≪いまだ巻き込み　余計な
負担ばかり　かけているのも→
I also have to face the fact that, even now, I'm involving him.
反省せねばならん≫
≪いや　吉野も吉野だ≫
No, Yoshino is to blame, as well.
He is too kind!
≪あやつは　人がよすぎる≫
≪断るべきところは断れ≫
He should refuse if he doesn't want to do something!
Because of that,
≪そんなんだから
私や真広などに振り回されて→
he keeps letting Mahiro and me pull him into terrible situations.
ひどい目にも遭うのだ≫
Not to mention, I hear that he has a girlfriend!
≪聞けば　あやつ
彼女もいるというではないか≫
≪私に付き従っている場合では
なかろう≫
He shouldn't be following me around!
≪振られても知らんぞ
うらなりめ！≫
He'd better not cry to me if he gets dumped... Cheater.
≪しかし　吉野ほどの男の彼女だ≫
Though...
Considering his own qualities,
≪よくできた娘なのだろうな…≫
Yoshino's girlfriend must be perfect.
ふん！
As if I care!
≪私の知ったことか！≫
≪（羽村）
あっ　行き方は分かりました。
I know how to get there, but...
でも
今は動いていないはずですよ。
But I don't think that train runs now.
I see.
そうですか…。
はい。　ん？
Right.
（葉風）えい！
（羽村）ううっ！
Who is that guy?
誰だ？　あの男は。
えっ　誰って…。
What are you—
You kicked him without even knowing who he was?
知らないのに蹴ったんですか？
なっ　なんで？
Yes.
Why?
何やら胸騒ぎがしてな。
まずかったか？
I felt uneasy.
Was that wrong?
はぁ～。
まあ　しかたありませんか。
I guess it can't be helped.
≪しっ　しかたないんだ!?≫
Can't be helped?!
（葉風）で　誰なんだ？
乗り換えを聞かれてただけですよ。
So, who is he?
He was just asking me about a transfer.
富士山に行くって。
（葉風）はあ？
He wanted to go to Mt. Fuji.
Huh?
Are you a fool?!
貴様はバカか！
あの周辺は
立ち入り禁止なのを知らんのか？
You don't know that area is off-limits?
≪確かに…→
It's true that the Tree of Exodus remaining in the area
あの地に残った絶園の樹は
異変の原因の一つと目され→
is believed to be partly responsible for the catastrophe,
許可された者以外
接近は禁じられている≫
so only authorized personnel can enter the area.
≪もっとも　あの周囲には→
And Ms. Hakaze put up basically permanent barrier around that Tree.
葉風さんが
半永久的な結界を張ったのだから→
各国から送り込まれた調査団も→
Even groups sent from other countries to
examine the Tree have been unable to enter.
絶園の樹に
接触できていないはずだ≫
（羽村）立ち入り禁止なのは
知っています。→
I know that it's off-limits.
But I sort of have to go anyway.
でも　行かないといけない
っていうか…。→
あの…　絶園の魔法使いの
うわさって知ってます？
Have you heard the rumors about the mage of Exodus?
あっ。
知っているどころか→
Not only have we heard, we know who spread the rumors.
そのうわさを流したヤツも
知っているぞ。
Huh?
えっ!?　じゃあ　話は早いのかな。→
Well, that may make things easier.
とにかく　僕が　その
絶園の魔法使いみたいなんですよ。
Anyway, I think I am that mage of Exodus.
You said your name is Hanemura?
（葉風）羽村といったな。
I'm Megumu. Hanemura Megumu.
（羽村）めぐむです。　羽村めぐむ。
When did you realize you had this power?
いつ　その力に気付いた？
１年くらい前です。→
About a year ago.
急に　体から
変な力が出せるようになって→
I was suddenly able to use a strange power.
And after the Tree of Exodus appeared, the power grew stronger,
そして　あの絶園の樹とかいうのが
現れたころから→
もっと強く
はっきり使えるようになったんです。
and I was able to use it more easily.
（葉風）≪１年くらい前…≫
About a year ago?
≪左門が絶園の樹復活を
本格化させたころか？≫
That's when Samon began enacting his plan for the Tree of Exodus.
（羽村）そこに
絶園の魔法使いのうわさを知って→
And then I heard the rumors about the mage of Exodus,
so I thought my power must have been related.
あっ　このための力だったんだ
って思ったんですけど→
違うんですか？
（葉風）違うと言えば信じるのか？
But maybe I was wrong?
If I said that wasn't it, would you believe me?
（羽村）えっと…　困ります。
Um... I don't know.
（葉風）困るな。　貴様の力は→
Stop being so uncertain!
That power is enough to make this building disappear in under a second.
この店　丸ごと
半瞬で消し去れるほどのものだぞ。
What?!
えっ!?　そっ　そんな…。
B-But...
（葉風）≪こやつ
本当に自覚がないのか？≫
He really has no idea?
≪自分が　世の理さえ
砕く力を持っているのを≫
He doesn't know he has the power to surpass the logic of this world?
（葉風）まあ
そう硬くならず　食べたらどうだ？
Well, you needn't be so nervous.
Eat up.
（羽村）あっ　はい。
Sure.
なっ　何？
What?
（葉風）貴様　魔法使いは→
Did you really think your were the only mage in this world?
自分一人だけだと思うか？
（羽村）えっ？
絶園の樹側の魔法使いが
いるなら→
If there are mages who side with the Tree of Exodus,
今　この世界を
支配している樹の側の→
then there should be mages who side with the Tree that rules this world.
魔法使いもいるはずだろう。
それが私だ。
And I'm one of them.
う…　うそ！
Are you serious?!
どうだ　魔法使い同士→
How about it? Shall we spar a bit?
ひとつ　手合わせしてみんか？
えっ？
（左門）幸い　滝川吉野は
姫様の恋心に気付かず→
Thankfully, Takigawa Yoshino doesn't realize the princess's feelings for him,
世界の命運を握った自覚もない。
and has no idea that he holds the fate of the world.
だが　あの少年→
However, that young man has the tendency
何かしら信じることがあれば→
to sacrifice others when he believes in something.
あらゆるものを犠牲にして
突っ走りそうな怖さがある。
If anything were to happen,
（左門）何かあれば　彼は
迷わず　姫様の背中を押すだろう。
I'm sure he wouldn't hesitate to give the princess a little push.
だから　そうなる前に→
So you're saying you want to kill Yoshino before that happens?
吉野を殺して排除しようってのか？
We're asking for your help to prevent that.
そうならぬよう
協力を頼んでいる。→
長いつきあいだと聞いた。
はぁ～。　あっ…。
I hear you've known him for a long time.
吉野の彼女は!?
そっちは無事なんだろうな!?
What about Yoshino's girlfriend? She'd better be safe.
そう聞いている。
関わらせたくないのか→
I heard that she's safe.
But I don't know who she is,
perhaps because he wishes to avoid involving her.
名前一つ　教えてくれんがな。
そうか。
I see.
≪好きな女が生きてんなら
吉野も　むちゃはしねぇだろう≫
If his girlfriend is alive,
I doubt that Yoshino will do anything reckless.
≪心配ねぇか≫
So no cause for concern.
（早河）
どうだ？　協力してくれるか？
How about it? Will you cooperate?
（回想）((僕の彼女のこと
誰にも話さないでください))
Please don't tell anyone about my girlfriend.
((知ってる人が増えると→
The more people who know,
the higher the chance Mahiro will accidentally find out.
真広の耳に　うっかり入る可能性も
高くなります))
((この状況で知られると
いかにも面倒でしょう？))
If he learned about it now, it would confuse things.
≪確かに　今は誰も
知らない方がいいかもしれない≫
I admit it may be for the best that no one knows yet,
≪ただ　そんな吉野君の心の内は→
but I wonder what Yoshino is really thinking.
実際　どうなっているんだろう？≫
吉野対策に手を貸すぜ。
I'll help with the Yoshino plan,
そのかわり　あんたらは
愛花を殺したヤツを見つける。
but you have to help me find Aika's killer.
その取り引きでいいか？
ああ。
Does that deal work for you?
Yes.
Fine.
分かった。　あんたらの
思いどおりに動いてやるよ。
I'll do whatever you guys want.
≪吉野　恩に着ろよ≫
You owe me, Yoshino.
I suppose I'll protect you, too.
≪ついでに　お前を守ってやるよ≫
（早河）
いつまで　不破真広に隠しておく？
How long do you intend to keep the truth from Fuwa Mahiro?
（左門）いずれ　彼も気付くだろう→
I'm sure he'll realize soon enough
滝川吉野が
絶園の魔法使いである可能性に。
that Takigawa Yoshino may be the mage of Exodus.
（葉風）羽村　少し離れろ。→
Hanemura, step back a bit.
その方が
お前も　魔法を使いやすかろう。
That should make it easier for you to use magic, as well.
Oh, okay.
（羽村）あっ　はい。
Isn't it dangerous to just start sparring like this?
いきなり手合わせって
危なくありませんか？
あやつが
どれほどの力と知識を持つか→
The truth is I won't know how powerful he is
結局　魔法を使わせてみなければ
分からんのも事実だ。→
unless I have him actually use his magic.
And I won't know whether he can kill or not, either.
それに　人を殺せるかどうかもな。
Fear not.
案ずるな。　はじまりの姫宮が
負けるようなら→
If the Princess of Genesis were to lose to him,
この世で
あやつに勝てる者はいないぞ。
then no one could stand against him.
（葉風）
ルールは簡単だ。　魔法を使って→
The rules are simple.
Use your magic to get me to, at least, kneel on the ground.
私の片膝でも
地面に着けさせろ。→
Then it is your victory.
そうすれば　貴様の勝ちだ。→
If you win, I will tell you everything you want to know.
勝てば　貴様の知りたいこと
すべて教えてやろう。
（羽村）えっと…　じゃあ
どうなれば　僕の負けでしょうか？
Um, then how will I know if I lose?
貴様の腕のどちらかが
逆方向に曲がったらだ。
If either one of your arms bends in the wrong direction.
Huh?
えっ!?
行くぞ。
Here we go.
樹の中の樹　大樹の中の大樹→
Tree within the tree,
great tree within the great tree,
我が名において聞き届けよ。
hear my words, and grant my wish!
なっ　何？　うわっ！
What?
（葉風）私ほどになれば
防御フィールドを自在に変化させ→
At my level, I can manipulate the defensive barrier as I please,
遠距離の相手を倒すことも可能だ。
and defeat opponents across great distances, as well.
≪こっ　これも魔法!?≫
Magic can do this?!
（葉風）≪羽村　貴様が本物なら→
Hanemura, if you are truly a mage,
これくらいの魔法
たやすく破壊できるぞ≫
you can neutralize this magic with ease.
≪貴様に私を殺し→
Do you have the power to kill me
この世の理を
変える力はあるのか？≫
and change the logic of this world?
（左門）
滝川吉野という少年の存在は→
Takigawa Yoshino's existence
はじまりの樹の理から→
is starting to separate itself
ことごとく
外れた結果をもたらしている。→
from the logic of the Tree of Genesis.
彼が富士にいなくても
姫様は　現代に戻りえたのだ。
Even had he not been at Mt. Fuji,
the princess would have been able to return to this time.
どういうことだ？
鎖部一族の中に→
What are you saying?
We were unable to find the killer
不破真広の妹を殺した犯人は
見つけられなかった。→
of Fuwa Mahiro's sister within the Kusaribe.
その時点で　姫様は→
At that point,
絶園の魔法使い犯人説を
導き出せたのだ→
the princess was able to theorize that the killer was the mage of Exodus.
滝川吉野が
いようが　いまいがな。→
Whether Takigawa Yoshino was there or not,
そうなれば　不破真広は
再度　姫様と手を組み→
Fuwa Mahiro would have rejoined the princess,
独力で　時間の檻を
破る方法を見つけるか→
and would have discovered how to destroy the prison of time.
あるいは
魔具を発動させるかして→
Or he would have activated the talisman,
姫様を戻す選択をしただろう。→
and figured out how to retrieve her.
はじまりの樹は
あの少年を必要としなかった。→
The Tree of Genesis had no need of the other young man.
逆に　あの少年によって→
It was actually because of him
はじまりの樹に
不利な現状がもたらされたのだ。
that the Tree of Genesis faced some inconsistencies.
ん？　ほう→
Well?
ようやく
魔法を使えるのを思い出したか？
Did you finally remember that you can also use magic?
≪そうだ　魔法だ≫
That's right.
I can use magic.
≪僕は　魔法が使える≫
≪あの人は
確かめようとしてるんだ→
She's testing me.
僕に世界を救う力があるか→
To see if I have the power to change the world,
この先　戦う覚悟があるか≫
and if I'll be able to fight.
She probably isn't my enemy.
≪あの人は　たぶん敵じゃない≫
≪やれる気がしてきた≫
I'm starting to feel like I can do it.
≪僕の遺伝子に
組み込まれていたものが→
I feel like something is awakening inside me.
次々と目覚めているような…≫
行きます！
Here I come!
さて　どこまで来れる？
Well then, let's see how far you get.
（羽村）くっ！
ドォーーン！
もう　それは通じません！
That won't work anymore!
斬り裂け！
Scatter!
パキーン！
あっ…　葉風さん！
Ms. Hakaze!
うっ　腕が…　腕が！
Your... Your arm!
どうしよう!?
（葉風）うろたえるな！
What am I gonna do?
Calm down!
Did you really think I couldn't regrow a limb?
この私が
腕一本　再生できんと思うか？
肉が散ったくらいで取り乱すな→
Stop sniveling over a little bit of flesh,
軟弱者！
you weakling!
（葉風）
ん？　本当に　逆に曲がったか。
His arm really did bend the other way.
脅かさないでくださいよ
葉風さん。
Don't scare me like that, Ms. Hakaze.
すまんな。　砕けると同時に→
Don't worry.
I cast a regeneration spell on my arm earlier that would activate upon serious damage.
再生する魔法を
かけておいたのだ→
あやつの反応を見るためにな。
I had to judge his reaction.
力は　確かに絶園のものだ。　だが→
His power is indeed that of Exodus.
But he isn't able to kill anyone.
こやつに人は殺せんな。
えっ？
Huh?
（葉風）あらゆるものを
破壊して揺るがぬ絶園の心を→
I don't believe this boy has the heart of Exodus,
この者が持つとは思えない。
the ability to destroy without mercy.
（左門）滝川吉野は
あえて　状況を複雑にし→
Takigawa Yoshino
has complicated the situation,
and has somehow made the princess
それらが　なぜか
解決される異常性を突きつけ→
はじまりの樹への不信感を
姫様に抱かせた。→
begin to doubt the Tree of Genesis.
そして…。
その心まで奪っていった。
And also...
He stole her heart while he was at it.
はじまりの樹の物語を狂わせ→
I can't think of anyone who could disrupt the story of the Tree of Genesis
その理を曲げた
イレギュラーな存在など→
絶園の魔法使い以外
まず考えられん。
besides the mage of Exodus.
（早河）
彼が　絶園の魔法使いだとすると→
If he is the mage of Exodus,
見事な仕事をしていることになる。
then he's quite competent at his job.
魔法を使わずして
はじまりの樹の理をゆがめ→
Without using magic, he has disrupted the Tree of Genesis,
その命運を　ほぼ握ってみせた。
ああ。　だが…。
and holds its fate in his hands.
Indeed, but...
Hello?
≪だが　彼が絶園の魔法使いなら→
But if he is the mage of Exodus,
不破真広の妹を殺したのも
滝川吉野となる≫
that would also make him the one who killed Fuwa Mahiro's sister.
Can I even convince myself of that possibility?
≪そこまで言い切れるか？≫
Hey, guys...
（山本）ちょっといい!?
うん？
吉野君から
絶園の魔法使いが見つかったけど→
It's Yoshino.
He says they found the mage of Exodus,
and he wants to talk to you.
そっちに　よこしていいかって…。
kimi no utatta hanauta ga
The song you hummed
boku no hanauta to kasanatta
and the song I hummed were the same
yoku aru koto kamoshirenai kedo
Maybe this is not so rare,
tokubetsu datte omoitainda
but I'd like to believe it's special
tokidoki fuan ni mo naru kara
Sometimes everyone feels anxious
tsui mata sagashite shimaundayo
and we wind up seeking it again
me ni mienai ito no youna
Like an invisible string,
futari wo tsuyoku tsunagi au mono
it is what connects us two
tatoe hoka no dare ga waratte mo
Even if others laugh about that,
boku wa tsuyoku shinjiteru kara
I believe it exists,
ima mo zutto zutto negatte iruyo
and so I keep on wishing even now
futari de iru mirai wo
for a future where we are together
mae wo muite aruite yuku yo
I will look ahead and walk
hitori kiri janai kara
because I am not alone
itsu no hi ka kimi to hora unmei datta ne tte
I hope we can one day laugh and say "Hey, it was destiny"
issho ni waraeru to ii na
Wouldn't that be nice?
She's my girlfriend, we've been dating since my junior year,
（羽村）高校２年のときから
つきあってる彼女で→
and her skin is white as snow, so I call her Yu!
肌が雪みたいに白いから
ゆっちゃんって呼んでるんだ。
（夏村）呼ばんでください。
お前　ストーカーか　なんかか？
Please do not call me.
Are you a stalker?
（哲馬）禁断の言葉を…。
（山本）まずいじゃない　それ！
The forbidden word...
That's not good!
（左門）しっ　しかし
けっ　計画の詳細も知らないまま…。
B-B-But without knowing the plan...
（葉風）いちゃいちゃしてるな。
よくやりますね。
You're being a flirt.
You do that a lot.
Episode 15
You Seem to Be
Plotting Something